<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Introduction to Probability and Statistics at Reed College</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Introduction to Probability and Statistics at Reed College</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: Foundations of Inference</title>
      <link>/post/2018/02/19/week-5-foundations-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/02/19/week-5-foundations-inference/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Foundations of Inference: Mythbusters Reading Chapter 2, p. 61-72   Tuesday  Lab 5: Benford’s Law   Wednesday  Lab 5 Questions Hypothesis Testing via Randomization   Friday  Hypothesis Testing (Continued) Slides   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: Foundations of Inference</title>
      <link>/post/2018/02/19/week-5-foundations-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/02/19/week-5-foundations-inference/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Foundations of Inference: An Analogy Reading Chapter 2, p. 72-85 Slides   Tuesday  Lab 5: No Lab this week.   Wednesday  Practice Midterm Review   Friday  Null Distributions via Probability Theory   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Random Variables</title>
      <link>/post/2018/02/12/week-4-random-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/02/12/week-4-random-variables/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Random Variables Reading Appendix A, p. 315 - 323 HW 4. - Due next Monday   Tuesday  Data Wrangling   Wednesday  Random Variables (continued) Fundamental Probability Distributions Bernoulli Trials dplyr Reading Appendix A, p. 315 - 323   Friday  Fundamental Probability Distributions Binomial Distribution Quiz 2   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Probability Foundations</title>
      <link>/post/2018/02/05/week-2-probability-foundations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/02/05/week-2-probability-foundations/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Pobability Foundations (continued) Outcomes and Events Reading Appendix A, p. 295-306 HW 3 - Due next Monday   Tuesday  Lab 3: Visualization   Wednesday  Pobability Foundations (continued) Honest and Thief Simulation Reading Appendix A, p. 306-316   Friday  Pobability Foundations (continued) Conditional Probability Reading Appendix A, p. 306-316   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Describing Data</title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/29/week-1-intro-to-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/29/week-1-intro-to-data/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Describing Data - Graphical Example Plots in R Reading p. 19-30 HW 2: Due next Monday MTH-141 Suvey   Tuesday  Lab 2: Sampling   Wednesday  Describing Data - Numerical Reading p. 19-30 Slides Data Camp: Exploratory Data Analysis   Friday  Probability Foundations Quiz Reading Appendix A, p. 295-306   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Intro to Data</title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/17/week-1-intro-to-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/17/week-1-intro-to-data/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Taxonomy of Data Reading p. 1-8 HW 1: Due next Monday MTH-141 Suvey Data Camp: Introduction to R   Tuesday  Lab 1 due Thursday at 11:59 pm   Wednesday  Data Collection for Inference Reading p. 9-16 Slides   Friday  Study Design  Experiments Observational Studies  Slides   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo XMin</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labs</title>
      <link>/labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labs/</guid>
      <description>We meet in the laboratory (ETC 211) every Tuesday to tinker around with data and statistics. Our tool of choice is R, software that vastly amplifies your power to explore, visualize, and model data. Reed&amp;rsquo;s RStudio Server is accessible by going to https://rstudio.reed.edu/ and using your college login.
Every week you&amp;rsquo;ll be working with a new data set and organizing your work in an RMarkdown document. You should complete work on your lab by Thursday at 11:59 PM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Sets</title>
      <link>/problemsets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/problemsets/</guid>
      <description>Weekly problem sets to reinforce the concepts from the reading as well as the material that we address in class. You’re encouraged to work on the problem sets with fellow students, though you’ll both need to turn in your own work. Problem sets are due every Monday at the beginning of class.
Problem set guidelines:
Remove all paper fringes and staple all pages Problem set number, date, and name should be clearly stated Write or type out all work and calculations for computational questions and provide clear explanations for yes/no questions Problem sets should be neat and easy to read (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Age of Data, where information is all around us, helping us live happier, healthier lives. Or does it? Do we know yet if cell phones cause cancer? Have we come to a decision on whether we should be eating lots of meat or none at all to stay healthy? Despite all of this information, it can be challenging to turn it into the knowledge from which we can make sound decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>