<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Introduction to Probability and Statistics at Reed College</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Introduction to Probability and Statistics at Reed College</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6: Inference</title>
      <link>/post/2018/03/05/week-7-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/03/05/week-7-inference/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Normal Distribution Statistical Errors Reading Chapter 2, p. 85-107   Tuesday  Lab 7: Inference for Catagorical Data   Wednesday  Hypothesis Tests Review Practice Slides   Friday  Sampling Distribution Confidence Intervals The Bootstrap Slides   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6: Foundations of Inference II</title>
      <link>/post/2018/02/26/week-6-foundations-inference-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/02/26/week-6-foundations-inference-ii/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Foundations of Inference: An Analogy Reading Chapter 2, p. 72-85 Slides   Tuesday  Lab 6: The Building Blocks of Inference   Wednesday  Approximating the Null Distribution Central Limit Theorem   Friday  Infer Package Overview Midterm 1   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: Foundations of Inference</title>
      <link>/post/2018/02/19/week-5-foundations-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/02/19/week-5-foundations-inference/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Foundations of Inference: Mythbusters Reading Chapter 2, p. 61-72   Tuesday  Lab 5: Benford’s Law   Wednesday  Lab 5 Questions Hypothesis Testing via Randomization   Friday  Hypothesis Testing (Continued) Slides   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Random Variables</title>
      <link>/post/2018/02/12/week-4-random-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/02/12/week-4-random-variables/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Random Variables Reading Appendix A, p. 315 - 323 HW 4. - Due next Monday   Tuesday  Data Wrangling   Wednesday  Random Variables (continued) Fundamental Probability Distributions Bernoulli Trials dplyr Reading Appendix A, p. 315 - 323   Friday  Fundamental Probability Distributions Binomial Distribution Quiz 2   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Probability Foundations</title>
      <link>/post/2018/02/05/week-2-probability-foundations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/02/05/week-2-probability-foundations/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Pobability Foundations (continued) Outcomes and Events Reading Appendix A, p. 295-306 HW 3 - Due next Monday   Tuesday  Lab 3: Visualization   Wednesday  Pobability Foundations (continued) Honest and Thief Simulation Reading Appendix A, p. 306-316   Friday  Pobability Foundations (continued) Conditional Probability Reading Appendix A, p. 306-316   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Describing Data</title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/29/week-1-intro-to-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/29/week-1-intro-to-data/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Describing Data - Graphical Example Plots in R Reading p. 19-30 HW 2: Due next Monday MTH-141 Suvey   Tuesday  Lab 2: Sampling   Wednesday  Describing Data - Numerical Reading p. 19-30 Slides Data Camp: Exploratory Data Analysis   Friday  Probability Foundations Quiz Reading Appendix A, p. 295-306   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Intro to Data</title>
      <link>/post/2018/01/17/week-1-intro-to-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/01/17/week-1-intro-to-data/</guid>
      <description>Monday  Taxonomy of Data Reading p. 1-8 HW 1: Due next Monday MTH-141 Suvey Data Camp: Introduction to R   Tuesday  Lab 1 due Thursday at 11:59 pm   Wednesday  Data Collection for Inference Reading p. 9-16 Slides   Friday  Study Design  Experiments Observational Studies  Slides   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>